Avi Lad

Software Engineer

in www.linkedin.com/in/avilad0/ 🕠 www.github.com/Avilad0/

https://avilad0.github.io/

Profile

Software Engineer, Computer Enthusiast, Problem Solver and Leader. Interested in Software Development. Development, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing and data analysis in finance and want to build my career in these fields. I am not limiting myself to any programming language or tool and I am open to work with different technologies. Currently working as Software Engineer at OpsHub Inc. Want to innovate and aid in the ever growing quest of building a smarter and advance world. Served as a programming tutor to peers. I am also geeked about financial markets.

Experience

OpsHub, Inc.

Software Engineer

May 2021 – present | Ahmedabad, India

• Worked on enhancement of existing code for end-systems, moving code to new framework, adding new DB connection feature, solving bugs and adding automation for different scenarios of integration of ALM systems and the installation of the product using Java, Apache Ant, MySQL and Oracle DB.

OpsHub, Inc. &

Software Engineer Intern

Jan 2021 - May 2021 | Ahmedabad, India

- Got 1 month training for concepts of integration and migration, using the OIM software for different ALM systems and overview of the codebase.
- Worked on solving customer bugs related to errors in reading API responses, unexpected product behaviour and adding automation related to the improvement using java.

Encode - The Computer Science Club of PDPU Vice President

|u| 2019 - |u| 2020

- Organized Workshops and Competitions related to Programming, Alexa, Web/APP development, Competitive coding competitions.
- Teaching peers coding and discussing new topics in technology.
- Supervising a team of 25 tech-students.

ORSP, PDPU

Web Development Intern

Nov 2019 - Apr 2020

- Integrating Scopus and Web of Science Data into University Website using APIs.
- Designing and coding new pages for the Website.

ShopX

Android Developer

Aug 2018 - Dec 2018 | Ahmedabad, India

• Developed the initial design and coded the Android app for the e-commerce StartUp.



Umiya Social Trust

Intern

Jun 2018 - Jul 2018 | Valsad, India

- Teaching Rural Students Basics of Computer.
- Volunteering for Events Organized by the NGO.

Education

Pandit Deendayal Petroleum University Bachelor of Technology(B.Tech.) in Computer Engineering

2017 – 2021 | Gandhinagar, India

CGPA: 9.6/10

Vallabh Ashram [CBSE]

12th Grade [Physics, Chemistry, Maths, Computer Science, English]

2017 | Valsad, India Percentage: 92.8%



Projects

Poem Generator using Stacked LSTM

- Used Stacked-LSTM Model to Train poems of prominent Medieval English Poets using Keras.
- It generates readable poem relating to the poetic style of Medieval Poets with some meaning based on Seed Text Input.

Voice Based Smart Home

• Using Raspberry Pi and Relays integration at switch boards connecting using Home-Wifi and using mobile voice input to R-Pi to initiate ON/OFF of the particular appliance

Music Streaming over Local Area Network

- Used Python Socket Library
- Stream music over a LAN without connecting to Internet
- It uses a Client-Server model to deliver music

Database Management System for Incubation

• Created Database Management system for Incubation center using SQL



Natural Language Processing in TensorFlow -Coursera

Intro to TensorFlow for Deep Learning - Udacity

Android Basics - Udacity

Social Networks - NPTEL (IIT-Madras)(Gold Medal)

Programming, data structures and algorithms using Python – NPTEL (IIT-Madras)(Gold Medal)

SQL - Statement of Accomplishment by **Stanford University**